討伐軍の突入から およそ３０分
But he's not out of reach.
宮殿内で繰り広げられた 激しい攻防をよそに
I need more training in Nen...
城の外では　今も おびただしい数の人民達が
To find a power that's as strong as Hisoka's!
よし　充電完了。
I didn't have time to prepare anything. It's not a big deal, whatever is fine.
見られてる
Three. Is she always like this? Four. Five.
しかも
Pretty much. Six. Let's move fast! Seven. Eight.
俺は多分　こいつを知ってる
Nine.
面影を残しながらも
Won't that take a while?
以前のパームではないことが 明白な　その姿が
Want me to pack some food for you? That's okay!
キルアの神経を 激しく波立たせた
We'll find something to eat in the forest.
勝算はある パームは近づいて来た
Gon and his friend are rather late. It's been a while since he
was last on this island.
パームか？
And he's brought his first friend along.
俺が視線を感じた以上 俺より前に パームも俺に気付いていたはず
I'm sure they won't be back until it's late.
前に言っていた自身の能力
You're right...
) ((私の能力を使えば 容易なことよ))
Maybe I should take some
food out to them.
恐らく　千里眼に近い
Hey, Gon.
パームが今いた場所からは 俺を直接見ることは できなかった
What are you going to do now?
別の方法で俺を見たとしか 考えられないからだ
For now, I'll rest up here
そして　パームが もし敵ならば遠ざかったはず
while I gather information... The information I'll need before I go
to Yorknew to look for my dad.
千里眼は 離れてこそ有効な技だし
Oh...
敵なら　もう 俺への記憶はないはずだから
What should I do?
近づいたってことは
Huh? You should stay here and then
go to Yorknew with me!
パームは俺を
Yeah, I'm coming with you.
俺達を覚えてる
That wasn't what I meant.
キル…アね。
I was thinking you're sort of admirable.
やっぱり… 記憶がある！
I don't really have anything
I want to do like you do.
こんな姿になった私を もう　ゴンは嫌いになるかしら？
Though there are plenty of
things I don't want to do. I don't want to stay in that house... Or inherit the family business.
ゴンは見てくれで ひとを判断しないよ。 …ってか　まず嫌われてるって 前提はないわけね。
I guess I'm a little jealous. Killua...
相変わらず 憎ったらしい口　利くわね。
I think it's fun to be with you.
まぁ　いいわ。
Wh-What's that about?
あんたに同情してもらっても 一文の得にもならないし。
Whale Island is a place for fishermen to stay
during extended outings.
ゴンは　どこ？ ゴンは　ピトーについている。
There aren't too many native residents.
あいつは…。
There's one other kid here that's
around my age, and she's a girl.
俺が見えて
So you're my first friend who's the same age.
ゴンが見えないのは何でだ？
My situation was similar...
どうしたの？ あ…。
I spent all my time learning how to kill.
俺を見つけたのは　たまたまか？ はぁ？　何言ってんの？
You were my first friend. Do you have fun when we're together?
あんたのほうが そこ曲がって来たんでしょ？
I guess, yeah.
違うね！ 俺は　お前の視線に気付いた。 こっちに来たのは　そのせいだ。
Then let's stick together! We can travel around and
see the world together!
お前が先に気付いたはずだ。
Don't you ever feel embarrassed
saying that stuff?
面倒くさいガキ。
I'll be looking for my dad.
ゴンは　どこ？ 俺の質問に答えてからだ。
You'll be looking for what you want to do.
俺が気付いたパームの視線は 実際に俺を見ていた時のもの？
It'll be a blast!
ならばパームは　俺を見つけて
Yeah.
すぐに俺から遠ざかった？
Doesn't sound too bad.
そして　追って来る俺を 千里眼で見て　きびすを返し 近づいたように見せかけた？
Okay! I'll help you look for your dad until
I discover what I want to do! Okay!
最後よ。
Oh, what's your mom doing?
教えねえよ。 敵だろ　お前。 うっ　うっ…。
It's hard asking about my dad,
but asking about my mom is even harder. Since Mito-san raised me by herself, it would feel wrong to ask her that...
私は　間違っていた。
my parents died in a traffic accident. She was worried that I
might end up like my dad
力の使い方を。
if I learned he was alive and a Hunter...
持て余すほどの激情なら…。
And she was right.
素直に身を任せれば よかったのだわ！
When I found out about my dad, I kind of figured that my
mom was probably dead.
こ…　こいつ　ヤバい！
So I've always thought of Mito-san as my mom.
ため込むくらいなら吐き出す。
She's the only mom I have.
お前を ぶっ殺したい気持ちとかさ！
So there's nothing for me to ask. I don't need to. I see.
つっ…。
My mom starts crying the second
I say I want to go outside!
アハハハ…！
She actually goes into hysterics!
After that...
アハハハ…！
I'm going to look for my dad.
その役割は もっぱら防御にあり
What's this? Something Ging left with me.
真に恐るべきは
Huh? He asked me to give this to you
when you became a Hunter.
守りを　強堅な髪の鎧に 委ねることでこそ可能な
My dad left this for me...
全身全霊を込めた殴打である
I'll tell you everything I know about Ging.
ぐっ…。
Ging is my cousin.
) )
My oldest memory of him is of his back. I was always running after him.
パームは　もともと強化系
I think back then, I was three...
能力が　ツボにハマると こんなにも変わるのか
I have the feeling that I was
always looking at his back.
完璧にガードしても ダメージが… 長期戦になったら 完全に不利だ
At age twelve, Ging left the
island to take the Hunter Exam, just like you did.
それでも 逃げるわけにはいかない
He suddenly said that
he was leaving the island.
もう　ゴンの精神は限界
When I asked him why, he told me this...
ピトーを待つことで　やっと つながっている状態なんだ
"There's something that I want."
ヒヒっ。
He never told me what it
was that he wanted.
絶対に会わせられない
Actually, it was just me making a fuss.
たとえ　元のパームの心が 残っていても…
But I never got to see Ging again
before he left the island.
今は　マイナス！
You were originally told that your parents died in a
traffic accident, right?
くっ…。
That was what happened to Mito's parents.
パーム！ ん？
After that, Ging's father went missing on a fishing trip.
何で　ゴンを捜してるんだ？ 理由次第じゃ 居場所を教えてやってもいいぜ。
Both of my sons ended up passing away.
はぁ？　何　いまさら。
Yes...
理由なんてないわ 会いたいからよ。
All that happened after he left.
どうせ近くでしょ？ 自力で捜すわよ。
Ten years later, Ging returned to the island.
あんたを　ぶち殺してからね！
When he returned, he came carrying you, and you were still a baby.
俺もテンパってて 敵とか言っちゃったけど
When I asked about your mother,
he'd only say that they were separated.
外見が変わろうが お前は　パームなんだろ？ ゴンは　苦しんでる。
I was about to agree to look after you,
when I heard a loud, "Don't be silly!"
尊敬する人を無残に変えられて。
I imagine everyone on the island heard it.
その人は　今 心すら奪われてるんだ。
Grandma, you don't need to mention that!
それをした張本人と ゴンは　向かい合ってる！
Anyhow, I knew we couldn't
count on him to raise you.
そこへ　お前までが その姿で　いきなり現れたら…。
So we don't know anything
about your mother.
ゴンは　もう… まともで　いられなくなる。
Mito even yelled, "Don't you ever come back!"
while she cried... Grandma! Anyway, Ging left this with us then.
だから　必ず 最初に あいつの名前を呼んでくれ。
This girl's tried to throw it away
so many times... That's because you always
put it back where it was!
「ゴン」って。
If you wanted to get rid of it, you should have buried or burned it,
rather than tossing it in the trash can.
「大丈夫」って言って。
Do you understand?
パームのことばっか心配してたよ。
Ging...
ゴンを安心させてやってよ。
Ging... Ging... Yeah, I'll use that.
時間稼ぎ
Tell me more about what Ging was like when he was little!
会わせるつもりは毛頭ない
Huh?
そのはずだった
Does it sound weird for me
to use his name? Somehow, it feels more natural.
あいつを…　少しでも…
You want to hear what Ging
was like as a child? Yeah!
楽にしてやってくれ。 それは　もう… パームにしか　できないんだ！
Hey, did Ging have any friends his age? No, he didn't.
他の…　誰にも…
So I always wanted him to play with me, but he would always run off.
できないんだよ。
You were always getting lost.
俺じゃ… できないんだ!!
Honestly, you only remember
the embarrassing stuff! You followed Ging into the mountains, but then you didn't come back. When Ging returned by himself, the whole village panicked.
And that happened several times.
口に出したことで
But when we went to look
for you in the mountains, Ging was always the first to find you.
キルアが　ずっと抱えていた せきが切れた
No matter where you hid... After a few times, people started wondering if you
two were just playing pranks.
おぉ！　隙だらけだ。
Well, you always hid in places that were impossible to locate.
予定変更　今　殺れ！　１号！
It was like you didn't want to be found. Really?
ノヴと全く同じ結末
I guess so...
プフが　ゆっくりと 音もなく迫って来るのを見て パームは　覚悟を決めた
Oh, that reminds me of this other time. Ging and I were...
しかし ピトーによって阻止された
Oh?
極寒の中　身震いを止めることが 不可能であるのと同様に 凶悪なオーラに　さらされた瞬間
I see. So this is the box. Huh?
反射的にオーラで身を守った パームを誰も責められない
How do you open it?
そのオーラに興味を示し
Yeah, I tried a bunch of methods, but it wouldn't open.
食事を取らない王の許しを得て
Mind if I use force?
ピトーとプフは
Go ahead.
彼女を実験兵士の 第１号とすることにした
Okay...
過去の記憶が残る傾向にある
It's no use. This is no ordinary box.
とりわけ　すでに 念能力を身につけている者に
I should be able to twist
open an ordinary steel box.
その傾向は顕著である 過去の記憶は 兵士の育成に当たり
And since we don't know what's inside,
we can't break the box.
益もあり害もあった
It's not making a sound.
害をもたらす事例の大部分は
Your dad said to give this to you once you
became a Hunter, right?
記憶と感情が 結び付いた場合に生じる
Yeah, that's what I heard.
そういう結論に達した２匹は ピトーの「ドクターブライス」で
Once you became a Hunter...
パームの脳の感情と記憶を つなぐ部位を破壊した
I get it...
記憶を残す者ほど 繭からの再生が早いことは
I figured it out! Gon, there's one thing we haven't tried yet!
ヂートゥやレオルでの 実験によって立証済みであった
Huh? Something you have as a Hunter
that you didn't have before.
速やかに 静かに人類を制するためには
Oh, I know! My Hunter License!
記憶を残しつつ 意のままに操ることが最上
But there isn't an opening for the card... No, that isn't it.
パームは 格好の被験者となった
I meant Nen...
私は…
There's another box inside.
ん!?
These are just steel plates.
１号じゃ　ない!!
It appears nothing was connecting them.
あんた達
This is...
アリの手先になんか 死んでもならない!!
I know! This is like the pattern on the promise
thread Wing-san gave me.
キルア
Bingo!
あんたのおかげよ。
A ring and a cassette tape...
頭の中に境があって
And a memory card?
気持ちと体がバラバラなのに
Look. That pattern is on the back of this ring.
自分じゃ　どうもできない。
You should take care before you put it on.
起きてから　ずっと　そうだった。
Really? You think that Ging
あんたが境を外してくれたの。
might try to hurt me? Just to be safe.
自分が無力だなんて思わないで。
Well, we can start by listening to the tape.
私がゴンのため
Oh, can you copy it? Sure, why?
何かできるなら喜んでする。
Just to be safe.
チッ。 どうした？
So you became a Hunter, too. Anyway, I have a question for you.
急がば回れ 兵士には　記憶も感情も 不要ってことですね
Do you want to see me?
しかし　それは ピトーの能力を借りずに済む
It was the first time Gon had
heard his father's voice. Ging appeared
私１人でも 兵士を生産できるということ
to have read Gon's mind when he recorded his question.